export const chapter = "Chapter - 15: Earth Movements and Landforms  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What causes endogenic movements on Earth?",
        optionA: "Wind and rain",
        optionB: "Internal forces within the Earth",
        optionC: "Running water and glaciers",
        correctAnswer: "B) Internal forces within the Earth",
      },
      {
        question: "How many major tectonic plates are there on Earth?",
        optionA: "5",
        optionB: "10",
        optionC: "6",
        correctAnswer: "C) 6",
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a result of exogenic forces?",
        optionA: "Earthquakes",
        optionB: "Volcanoes",
        optionC: "Erosion",
        correctAnswer: "C) Erosion",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the primary cause of volcanic eruptions?",
        optionA: "Heavy rainfall",
        optionB: "Movement of tectonic plates",
        optionC: "Wind force",
        correctAnswer: "B) Movement of tectonic plates",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the Richter Scale used to measure?",
        optionA: "Wind speed",
        optionB: "Earthquake magnitude",
        optionC: "Temperature",
        correctAnswer: "B) Earthquake magnitude",
      },
      {
        question: "How are earthquakes measured with a seismograph?",
        optionA: "Temperature changes",
        optionB: "Wind speed",
        optionC: "Tremors",
        correctAnswer: "C) By tremors",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the point above the focus of an earthquake on the Earth's surface called?",
        optionA: "Centre",
        optionB: "Epicentre",
        optionC: "Apex",
        correctAnswer: "B) Epicentre",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What are the three types of volcanoes based on their activity?",
        optionA: "Young, middle-aged, old",
        optionB: "Active, dormant, extinct",
        optionC: "Erupting, resting, silent",
        correctAnswer: "B) Active, dormant, extinct",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What landforms are created by running water in the mountains?",
        optionA: "Sand dunes",
        optionB: "Valleys and plateaus",
        optionC: "Waterfalls, meanders, and lakes",
        correctAnswer: "C) Waterfalls, meanders, and lakes",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary cause of soil erosion according to the text?",
        optionA: "Earthquakes",
        optionB: "Human activity",
        optionC: "Glaciers",
        correctAnswer: "B) Human activity",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What makes itself manifest all around us in the form of rocks, soil, water, air, minerals, plants, animals, and other things?",
        optionA: "Nature",
        optionB: "Technology",
        optionC: "Civilization",
        correctAnswer: "Nature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Man first realized the value of ________, which he could gather to satisfy his needs.",
        optionA: "Fruits",
        optionB: "Leaves",
        optionC: "Animals",
        correctAnswer: "Fruits",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Man discovered fire and used it as a means to cook his food and ________ himself.",
        optionA: "Shelter",
        optionB: "Heat",
        optionC: "Educate",
        correctAnswer: "Heat",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The story of civilization is closely connected with man's learning to use different things in different ways. In using these things, he also learned how to convert a thing into a useful article; for example, he learned to make tools out of ________.",
        optionA: "Wood",
        optionB: "Stone",
        optionC: "Metal",
        correctAnswer: "Stone",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Early Man first found the value and utility of ________, which he could use as a tool.",
        optionA: "Water",
        optionB: "Fire",
        optionC: "Stone",
        correctAnswer: "Stone",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Without technology and skill, it is not possible to transform substances into ________.",
        optionA: "Food",
        optionB: "Resources",
        optionC: "Tools",
        correctAnswer: "Resources",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India has been rich in natural resources, yet it has remained poor because of non-availability of ________ and skill.",
        optionA: "Technology",
        optionB: "Education",
        optionC: "Money",
        correctAnswer: "Technology",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The value of a particular resource can change with time due to factors such as development in technology, varying needs of people, or availability of ________ materials.",
        optionA: "Substitute",
        optionB: "Rare",
        optionC: "Expensive",
        correctAnswer: "Substitute",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Some resources fall under more than one type. Let us know more about the following types of ________.",
        optionA: "Animals",
        optionB: "Resources",
        optionC: "Humans",
        correctAnswer: "Resources",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Sustainable development is meant to balance our needs such that we can conserve these resources for the ________.",
        optionA: "Past",
        optionB: "Present",
        optionC: "Future",
        correctAnswer: "Future",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "India has been poor despite its rich natural resources due to the lack of technology and skill.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Volcanoes are considered exogenic movements.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The Richter Scale measures wind speed during earthquakes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Glaciers move rapidly and erode rocks quickly.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Human activity, such as dams and deforestation, can positively impact the environment.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The epicenter of an earthquake is the point above the focus on the Earth's surface.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Himalayas have been formed due to folding in the earth's crust.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Erosion is a continuous process that does not occur everywhere on Earth.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Sustainable development aims to maximize resource depletion for immediate benefits.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Tsunamis are caused by earthquakes in the ocean bed.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
